A Guide to the William Faulkner Foundation Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Short Stories
  - A: Published
    - The Brooch., Autograph manuscript, 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - The Brooch., Carbon typescript, 16 p. (15 R, 1 v) on 15 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - The Brooch., Bound carbon typescript, 30 p. (30 R, 0 V) on 30 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Carcassonne., Typescript, 7 p. (7 R, 0 V) on 7 l. (Box Box 7.)
      With autograph corrections
    - Carcassonne., Typescript, 7 p. (7 R, 0 V) on 7 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - A Courtship., Carbon typescript 33 p. (22 R, 11 V) on 22 l. (Box Box 7.)
      With autograph corrections. See also " Shall Not Perish.
    - Death Drag., Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (22 R, 0 V) on 11 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Death Drag., Carbon typescript, 27 p. (27 R, 0 V) on 27 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Death Drag., January. 1932; Printed copy 10 p. (5 R, 5 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 7.)
      from Scribner's " Delta Autumn. " See Go Down, Moses.
    - Divorce in Naples., Autograph manuscript, 6 p. (6 R, 0 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Divorce in Naples., Carbon typescript, 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Doctor Martino., Autograph manuscript, 14 p. (14 R, 0 V) on 14 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Doctor Martino., Autograph manuscript, 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Doctor Martino., Typescript, 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Dry September., Autograph manuscript, 8 p. (8 R, 0 V) on 8 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Dry September., Carbon typescript, 19 p. (19 R, 0 V) on 19 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Dry September., (January. 1931); Printed copy 8 p. (4 R, 4 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from Scribner's
    - Dry September., (January. 1932); Printed copy 18 p. (9 R, 9 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from La Nouvelle Revue Francaise
    - Elly, Autograph manuscript, 7 p. (6 R, 1 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 8.)
      ("Selvage")
    - Elly, Typescript 14 p. (14 R, 0 V) on 14 l. (Box Box 8.)
      With autograph corrections. ("Selvage")
    - Elly, Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (11 R, 0 V) on 11 l. (Box Box 8.)
      An Error in Chemistry. See Knight's Gambit; Fool about a Horse. See The Hamlet.
    - Foxhunt, Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (11 R, 0 V) on 11 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Foxhunt, Typescript 26 p. (26 R, 0 V) on 26 l. (Box Box 8.)
      With autograph corrections.
    - Foxhunt, (Sept. 1931); Printed copy 12 p. (6 R, 6 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 8.)
      From Harper's. " Gold Is Not Always " See Go Down, Moses; " Go Down Moses " See Go Down, Moses; " Hand Upon the Waters " See Knight's Gambit; " The Hound " See The Hamlet.
    - Idyll in the Desert., Autograph manuscript, 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - A Justice., Autograph manuscript, 12 p. (10 R, 2 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - The Leg., Autograph manuscript, 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - The Leg., Carbon typescript, 26 p. (26 R, 0 V) on 26 l. (Box Box 8.)
      Lizards in Jamshyd's Courtyard, printed copy from The Saturday Evening Post, 8 p. (4 R, 4 V) on 4 l. (see Meriwether, p. 29 and 173)
    - Miss Zilphia Gant, Autograph manuscript, 9 p. (9 R, 0 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Miss Zilphia Gant, Bound typescript 18 p. (18 R, 0 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Miss Zilphia Gant, Carbon typescript, 23 p. (23 R, 0 V) on 23 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Miss Zilphia Gant, Certificate (Box Box 8.)
      copyright registration.
    - Mistral, Autograph manuscript, 19 p. (17 R, 2 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Mistral, Carbon typescript, 46 p. (46 R, 0 V) on 46 l. (Box Box 8.)
      Monk. See Knight's Gambit.
    - A Mountain Victory., Autograph manuscript, 18 p. (18 R, 0 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - A Mountain Victory., Carbon typescript, 42 p. (42 R, 0 V) on 42 l. (Box Box 8.)
      Mule in the Yard. " See The Town.
    - My Grandmother Millard., Typescript, 2 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 2 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - My Grandmother Millard., Carbon typescript, 4 p. (2 R, 2 V) on 2 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - My Grandmother Millard., Carbon typescript, 56 p. (43 R, 13 V) on 43 l. (Box Box 8.)
      The Old People. See Go Down, Moses and Big Woods; Pantaloon in Black. See Go Down, Moses.
    - Pennsylvania Station., Autograph manuscript, 8 p. (8 R, 0 V) on 8 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Pennsylvania Station., Autograph manuscript, 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Pennsylvania Station., Typescript, 2 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 2 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Pennsylvania Station., Typescript, 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Pennsylvania Station., Typescript, 21 p. (21 R, 0 V) on 21 l. (Box Box 8.)
      With autograph corrections. " A Point of Law. " See Go Down, Moses; " Race at Morning. " See Big Woods.
    - Red Leaves., Autograph manuscript, 12 p. (12 R, 0 V) on 12 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Red Leaves., Carbon typescript, 36 p. (36 R, 0 V) on 36 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Red Leaves., Printed copy 16 p. (8 R, 8 V) on 8 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from Saturday Evening Post
    - A Rose for Emily, Autograph manuscript, 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - A Rose for Emily, Carbon typescript, 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - A Rose for Emily, (April, 1930); Printed copy 6 p. (3 R, 3 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from Forum
    - A Rose for Emily, Printed copy 6 p. (3 R, 3 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from The Golden Book Magazine
    - A Rose for Emily, Printed copy 28 p. on 7 l. (Box Box 8.)
      in French, (uncut)
    - Shall Not Perish, Carbon typescript 49 p. (27 R, 22 V) on 27 l. (Box Box 8.)
      With autograph corrections. (Meriwether #25, a and c) Portions of " A Courtship on some versos.
    - Shall Not Perish, Typescript, 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 8.)
      with autograph corrections
    - Shingles for the Lord, carbon typescript, 32 p. (21 R, 11 V) on 21 l. (Box Box 8.)
      Smoke. See Knight's Gambit; Spotted Horses; Abraham's Children. See The Hamlet; Father Abraham. See The Hamlet.
    - The Tall Men., Carbon typescript, 18 p. (18 R, 0 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 8.)
      (Meriwether, #28)
    - That Evening Sun., Carbon typescript, 26 p. (26 R, 0 V) on 26 l. (Box Box 8.)
      (Meriwether, #27)
    - That Evening Sun., March 1931; Printed copy 12 p. (6 R, 6 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 8.)
      from The American Mercury (Meriwether, #27)
    - There Was A Queen, Autograph manuscript, 8 p. (8 R, 0 V) on 8 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - There Was A Queen, Typescript 25 p. (25 R, 0 V) on 25 l. (Box Box 8.)
      with corrections
    - There Was A Queen, Carbon typescript, 25 p. (25 R, 0 V) on 25 l. (Box Box 8.)
    - Thrift, Autograph manuscript, 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Thrift, Typescript, 18 p. (18 R, 0 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Thrift, Printed copy 8 p. (4 R, 4 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 9.)
      from The Saturday Evening Post. " Tomorrow. " See Knight's Gambit.
    - Turn About, Autograph manuscript, 16 p. (16 R, 0 V) on 16 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Turn About, Printed copy 10 p. (5 R, 5 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 9.)
      from The Saturday Evening Post
    - Victory, Autograph manuscript, 10 p. (9 R, 1 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Victory, Typescript, 54 p. (54 R, 0 V) on 54 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Victory, Typescript, 51 p. (51 R, 0 V) 51 l. (Box Box 9.)
  - B. Unpublished Short Stories
    An Absolution [ Apotheosis ]. See " The Fire on the Hearth.
    - Adolescence, typescript, 26 p. (26 R, 0 V) on 26 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - The Big Shot, typescript 37 p. (37 R, 0 V) on 37 l. (Box Box 9.)
      with autograph corrections. " The Fire on the Hearth. " See Go Down, Moses; " Knight's Gambit. " See Knight's Gambit.
    - Love, Autograph manuscript, 13 p. (13 R, 0 V) on 13 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Love, Miscellaneous autograph manuscript, 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Love, Typescript, 49 p. (49 R, 0 V) on 49 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Moonlight, carbon typescript, 16 p. (16 R, 0 V) on 16 l. (Box Box 9.)
      incomplete. " An Odor of Verbena, " see The Unvanquished.
    - Rose of Lebanon, autograph manuscript, 9 p. (9 R, 0 v) on 9 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Snow, Miscellaneous typescript, 4 p. (3 R, 1 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 9.)
    - Snow, Carbon typescript, 33 p. (18 R, 15 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 9.)
      Was, see Go Down, Moses.
    - Weekend Revisited, carbon typescript 19 p. (19 R, 0 V) on 19 l. (Box Box 9.)
      with autograph corrections. (not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 229). [#6074-a]
    - The Wishing Tree, Typescript 47 p. (47 R, 0 V) on 47 l. (Box Box 9.)
      with autograph corrections. (Meriwether #7) Published posthumously by Random House
    - The Wishing Tree, Typescript, 42 p. (42 R, 0 V) on 42 l. (Box Box 9.)
      missing p. 25 (not listed in Meriwether; see Massey p. 229) [#6074-a] Published posthumously by Random House
    - The Wishing Tree, Carbon typescript 42 p. (42 R, 0 v) on 42 l. (Box Box 9.)
      (not listed by Meriwether; see Massey p. 229) [#6074-a] Published posthumously by Random House
    - With Caution and Dispatch, Typescript, 2 p. (2 R, 0 v) on 2 l. (Box Box 9.)
      (Meriwether #8)
    - With Caution and Dispatch, Typescript 49 p. (47 R, 2 V) on 47 l. (Box Box 9.)
      with autograph corrections. (Meriwether #8)
    - [Untitled about "Frankie"], Carbon typescript, 23 p. (23 R, 0 V) on 23 l. (Box Box 9.)
      (Meriwether #9)
- Series III
  - A. Published Verse
    - Cathay, no date; typescript 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      with one holograph correction. Published first in The Mississippian (1919 November 12) and in the Oxford Eagle (1919 November 13). [Massey, p. 229]
    - April, no date; typescript, 2 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "I Will Not Weep for Youth...
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Knew I Love Once...
    - My Epitaph, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Spring, 1924 December 13; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - To a Virgin, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - [" Twilight "], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Beyond the hill the sun swam downward.. ." ( The Green Bough, X)
    - Vision in Spring, no date; typescript, 3 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Winter is Gone...
    - A Child Looks from his Window, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Marriage, no date; typescript, 4 p. (Box Box 9.)
      ( The Green Bough, II)
    - Philosophy, no date; typescript, 2 p. (Box Box 9.)
      w/AMs note on verso. ( The Green Bough, V)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Man Comes, Man Goes.. ." ( The Green Bough, VI)
    - [" Night Piece "], no date; typescript, 2 p. (Box Box 9.)
      w/AMs note on verso. First line: "Trumpets of sun in silence fall.. ." ( The Green Bough, VII)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "The Sun lay long upon the hills.. ." ( The Green Bough, IX)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "When evening shadows grew around.. ." (variant extra verse) ( The Green Bough, XI)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Young Richard, striding toward town.. ." ( The Green Bough, XII)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "When I was young and proud and gay.. ." ( The Green Bough, XIII)
    - Puck and Death, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      ( The Green Bough, XVI. Also, Mississippi Verse )
    - On Seeing the Winged Victory for the First Time, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      ( The Green Bough, XVII)
    - La Lune ne Grade Aucune Rancune, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Nativity, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Cleopatra, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "The Flowers That Died...
  - B. Published Verse
    - Adolescence, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - The Dancer, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Eunice, no date; typescript, 3 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - The Shepard's Love, no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - Dedication/ To Elise, 1924 December 5; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
    - [untitled], no date; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Sweet will it be to us who sleep...
    - [untitled], 1925 February 10; typescript, 1 p. (Box Box 9.)
      First line: "Where I am dead the clover loved of bees...
- Series IV: Writing for Television and Movies
  - The Big Sleep, no date; autograph manuscript 1 p. (Box Box 10.)
    dialogue, Vivian,
  - Continuous Performance, no date; carbon typescript, 38 p. (Box Box 10.)
    Pagination: 1-30, 30A, 31-37
  - Old Man, no date; typescript 22 p. (Box Box 10.)
    Story Line on Old Man, with autograph corrections, w/env. Pagination: 1-16, 16A, 16B, 17-20. Typescripts of portions of other manuscripts, including Shall Not Perish and Mississippi are on versos of pages following page 2.
  - Old Man, no date; Carbon typescript 26 p. (Box Box 10.)
  - Old Man, 1953 April 16; TLS carbon, 1 p. (Box Box 10.)
    Saxe Cummins to Martin Jurrow
  - One Way to Catch a Horse, no date; carbon typescript 36 p. (Box Box 10.)
  - Revolt in the Earth, no date; bound carbon typescript 62 p. (Box Box 10.)
    w/ cover, Also Warner Bros. house telegram, 1943 January 6, Robert Buckner to William Faulkner.
  - [untitled science fiction scenario], no date; typescript and carbon typescript 2 p. (Box Box 10.)
    Morningstar[?] see folder VIII-17
  - [untitled script concerning "Sarastro," "Anna," and "Rico"], no date; typescript, 32 p. (Box Box 10.)
    Pagination: 29-30, 56-58, 58A, 59-82, 113. Unidentified typescript on verso of page 113.
  - [untitled], no date (Box Box 10.)
    unproduced series, located on the versos of pages 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 11C of chapter xvii of The Mansion (Series IA, Item 20A) (not listed in Meriwether). [#6074-f]
- Series V: Miscellaneous Manuscripts (see Meriwether, p. 93)
  - [Introduction to The Sound and the Fury ], typescript, 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 10.)
  - From the Viking Portable Faulkner, carbon typescript, 12 p. (12 R, 0 V) on 12 l. (Box Box 10.)
    Appendix on Compson family,
  - From the Viking Portable Faulkner, carbon typescript, 36 p. (35 R, 1 V) on 35 l. (Box Box 10.)
    "Dilsey" section, pencilled notes on verso of last page concerning horseshow program.
- Series VI: Articles and Essays (See Massey, p. 230)
  - An Innocent at Rinkside., Carbon typescript 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 10.)
  - Mississippi., Carbon typescript 41 p. (40 R, 1 V) on 40 l. (Box Box 10.)
    with autograph corrections. [#6074-a]
  - A Note on Sherwood Anderson " [" Sherwood Anderson: An Appreciation "]., Carbon typescript, 9 p. (9 R, 0 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 10.)
    [#6074-a] " On Privacy: The American Dream: What Happened to It. " See under speeches, " Freedom American Style.
- Series VII: Speeches (See Massey, p. 230)
  - Freedom American Style., Miscellaneous typescript and autograph manuscript 27 p. (17 R, 10 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 10.)
    [#6074-a]
  - Nobel Prize Acceptance, 1950; printed copy 24 p. (Box Box 10.)
    "I Decline to Accept the End of Man," printed by Press of the Good Mountain, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, N. Y. [#6074-a] uncut page with cover.
  - Nobel Prize Acceptance, March 1951; (4 R, 1 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 10.)
    " William Faulkner's 'The Nobel Prize Speech,'" printed by Spiral Press, N. Y., 5 p. [#6074-a]
  - Pine Manor College commencement, 1953 June 8; Carbon typescript, 9 p. (9 R, 0 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 10.)
  - Southern Historical Association, 1955 November 19; Carbon typescript, 6 p. (6 R, 0 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 10.)
  - University High School commencement, 1951 May 28; Autograph manuscript 2 p. (2 R, o V) on 2 l. (Box Box 10.)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous Material Including Correspondence (not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 231)
  - Photograph of drawing of William Faulkner by Owen Crump. (Box Box 11.)
    [#6451]
  - Crayon drawing, 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 11.)
  - Bank note, 1924 January 26; 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 11.)
    in amount of $103.25 signed, John Faulkner III to order of " William, Faulkner. " [#6451]
  - Hardware store bill, 1931 December; 1 p. (Box Box 11.)
    to William Faulkner. [#6451] fragment
  - Printed account sheet, 1939 July 1; 1 sheet (Box Box 11.)
    from Quick Repair Shoe Shop to William Faulkner [#6451]
  - Typewritten fragments, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 11.)
    beginning, "Well, dear friends, here we are again. Back in our beloved school...
  - Three manuscript pages regarding M/S Minmagary., 4 p. (3 R, 1 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 11.)
  - One page pencil map of deer hunt. (Box Box 11.)
  - One typewritten page containing professional qualifications of unidentifiable scientist. (Box Box 11.)
    [#6451] [ Malcolm Franklin ?]
  - One autograph page list of cities between Oxford and Allentown with mileage distances (?) (Box Box 11.)
  - House accounts and other financial and numerical records., 8 p. (6 R, 2 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 11.)
  - The Dutchman's House, " by Charles Sibleigh, Paris, 1921; Typescript, 42 p. (including title page) (42 R, 0 V) on 42 l. (Box Box 11.)
  - Nobel Prize Address. See Speeches. (Box Box 11.)
  - Record of work sent to publishers, 1 cardboard sheet. 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 11.)
  - Papers, documents and envelopes, 1924-1926; 10 items (Box Box 11.)
    Relating to William C. Faulkner's service as Postmaster of the University of Mississippi. Items include: 1924 October 31, Receipt for Mail keys, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l.; 1924 October 31, Certificate for transfer of postal forms and funds, signed by " W. C. Faulkner, " Outgoing Postmaster and James W. Bell, Jr., Acting Postmaster, 1 p. on 1 l.; 1924 October 31, Receipt for Internal Revenue Documentary Stamp Fixed Credit at District Post Office, signed by James W. Bell, Jr. 1 p. on 1 l.; 1924 October 31, Receipt for stamps, forms, etc. signed by James W. Bell, Jr.; 1925 October 19, Form letter informing " M. C. Faulkner " of his accounting with the General Accounting Office, 1 p. on 1 l.; 1925 October 26, TL carbon, W. C. Faulkner to General Accounting Office, 1 p. on 1 l.; 1925 November 9, TLS, J. R. McCarl (signed by R. S. Tower ) to "Mr. M. C. Faulkner, " 1 p. on 1 l.; Forms, 2 p. on 2 l., and five envelopes of the General Accounting Office; 1926 March 3, Form letter from J. R. McCarl to " William C. Faulkner "; 1926 March 18, TLS, B. G. Lowrey to Phil Stone, 1 p. on 1 l. with enclosures of two statements of account for October 19 and November 9, 1925, 6 p. on 6 l.
  - Papers relating to William Faulkner's service in the Royal Air Force: (Box Box 11.)
    Autograph manuscript notes and drawings on aeronautics, 36 p. (19 R, 17 V) on 19 l.; Honorary Commission, 12 November 1920, of William Faulkner as 2nd Lieutenant, 1 p.; Covering letter for money order, 13 January 1919, R. A. F. to William Faulkner, 1 p.; Mimeographed letter, 21 November 1918, Imperial Royal Flying Corps to airmen and cadets regarding uniforms, 1 p.; Printed table of pay allowances in R. A. F., 1 p.
  - Two maps: (Box Box 11.)
    Carte des Environs de Paris, 1 p.; Lafayette County, Mississippi, Soil Map, 1912, 1 p.
  - Drafts of letters and fragments of drafts by William Faulkner: (Box Box 11.)
    1944 November 20, TL fragment, [ William Faulkner ] to "Mr. Ballinger," 1 p.; 1948 February 12, TL fragment, [ William Faulkner ] to Cleveland, 1 p. (date and address only).; 1948 June 18, TL, [ William Faulkner ] to [Howard] Hawks, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l.; 1948 June 29, TL, [ William Faulkner ] to Howard hHawks, 2 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 2 l.; "Monday," TL fragment, [ William Faulkner ] to Saxe [Commins], 1 p.; "Saturday," TL, [ William Faulkner ] to "Bill," 1 p.; "Saturday," TL with autograph corrections, [ William Faulkner ] to "The Editors, Commercial Appeal, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l. Brief, Unidentified typescript fragment [possibly from Requiem for a Nun ?] and autograph arithmetical notes on verso.; n. d., AL, [ William Faulkner ] to "Mr. Thompson," concerning " Spotted Horses, " 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l.
  - Letters to William Faulkner (Box Box 11.)
    (not listed in Massey) [#6451] Including: 1941 May 23, mimeographed LS, Clyde McGhee to [ William Faulkner ], 1 p.; 1941 May 23, TLS, William Herndon to William Faulkner, 1 p.; 1949 January 10, copy of TL, Random House to William Faulkner, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l. Unidentified typescript fragment on verso.; 1951 September 4, TLS, w/env, Saul N. Wernick to William Faulkner, 1 p.; 1951 September 4, TLS, w/env, Leighton M. Ballew to William Faulkner, 1 p.; [1951 September 5], one envelope, Random House to William Faulkner; n. d., A draft in pencil, unsigned, lacking addressee, concerning transfer of ownership of a horse, 2 p. (1 R, 1 V) on 1 l.
  - Xerox copies, 6 letters (Box Box 11.)
    #6451-c. (not listed in Massey) Including: 1929 February 15, TL, [ Harcourt, Brace ] to William Faulkner, 1 p.; 1929 February 18, TLS, William Faulkner to Mr. Harcourt, 1 p.; 1929 February 25, TL, [ Harcourt, Brace ] to William Faulkner, 1 p.; [1929 April 13], TLS, William Faulkner to Mr. Chase (of Harcourt, Brace ), 1 p.; 1933 July 19, TLS, William Faulkner to Sam Marx (of MGM Studios ), 1 p.; 1949 October 12, TLS, William Faulkner to Sam [Marx], 1 p.
  - Aperture Cards, 83 l. and copies there from, 108 p. (108 R, 0 V) on 108 l. (Box Box 11.)
    [#6451-b] including: poetry by Col. W. C. Faulkner; typescript poems by William Faulkner; 6 letters of William Faulkner to his "Aunt Bama"; 1 letter of William Faulkner to "May Bell"; the Nobel Prize Speech as published by the Spiral Press, 1951; A Catalogue of the Writings of William Faulkner, by Robert W. Daniel; numerous clippings, family letters and others material (none of this material listed in Massey).
  - Clipping from The Press-Scimitar [ Memphis ?], [14 September 1933 or 1934] (Box Box 11.)
    with a photograph of a plane being flown by William Faulkner. (not listed in Massey). [#6074-c]
  - Clipping from the Tennessee Commercial Appeal, 7 January 1951 (Box Box 11.)
    including an article by Jill Faulkner describing the Nobel Prize ceremonies. (not listed in Massey). [#6074-c]
  - miscellaneous non-manuscript material (Box Box 12.)
    Including Unidentified scraps, a typing paper box and envelopes that originally held manuscripts, old folders, etc. (The "Remcraft" folders in this box are not likely to have originated with Faulkner himself, but to have been used in an early cataloging system, such as Princeton's.